<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NASA | Bin Chen</title>
    <link>https://binchensun.github.io/tag/nasa/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://binchensun.github.io/tag/nasa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>NASA</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 Bin Chen </copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://binchensun.github.io/media/icon_hu75e2917fbf1e73e1b7889fed0e47edf0_202296_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>NASA</title>
      <link>https://binchensun.github.io/tag/nasa/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Postdoc Position</title>
      <link>https://binchensun.github.io/news/postdoc_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://binchensun.github.io/news/postdoc_2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Solar Radio Group of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://centers.njit.edu/cstr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Center for Solar-Terrestrial Research&lt;/a&gt; at the New Jersey Institute of Technology has an immediate opening for a Post-Doctoral Research Associate to carry out original research in the area of solar flare physics. The researcher will utilize radio data from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ovsa.njit.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Expanded Owens Valley Solar Array&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://science.nrao.edu/facilities/vla/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Karl G. Jansky Very Large Array&lt;/a&gt;, as well as multi-wavelength data obtained by other ground-based or spaceborne telescope facilities, to study energy release and particle acceleration in solar eruptive events. The researcher will also have the opportunity to join a multi-institutional collaboration to work on joint observation–model studies of solar eruptions, and to contribute to EOVSA operation and the development of next-generation solar radio instrumentation. The appointment is initially for one year, with the possibility of renewal for up to two additional years contingent upon the availability of funding and mutual satisfaction. Applications will be accepted until the position is filled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essential Functions include reducing, analyzing, and interpreting data from the EOVSA, VLA, and other telescope facilities; 2) Publishing relevant results in peer-reviewed journals and presenting at professional meetings. Successful applicants are expected to have a Ph.D. in physics, astrophysics, space physics, or a closely related field. The candidate is expected to have experience in data analysis of solar data, an understanding of basic solar physics, plasma physics, and radiative transfer, and a working knowledge of Python/IDL and Linux/Mac. Experience in radio interferometry and synthesis imaging will be considered a plus but not a prerequisite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application consists of a complete CV (including a list of publications), a research statement (1-2 page), and names and contact information for three references.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
